Charles Mingus Collection
Music Division, Library of Congress
- Music (Box 1-44)
  - Manuscript Music (Box 1-29, Box 32-44)
    - Manuscript Music by Others (Box 30, Box 42)
      - Body and soul [1930] / music by John Green; words by Edward Heyman and Robert Sour., Instrumental parts, tenor sax and trombone only; 2 leaves; 31.5 cm.; Note: Copyist's manuscripts in ink.; Reference no.: 200.; Access points: Green, John Heyman, Edward Sour, Robert (Box-folder 30/6)
      - Can you blame me? / by George Joyner., Lead sheet; 2 p.; 32 cm.; Note: Holograph in pencil. Includes lyrics in ink on verso.; Access points: Joyner, George (Box-folder 30/7)
      - Candy [1945] / by Mack David, Joan Whitney and Alex Kramer., Lead sheet fragment; 1 p.; 31.5 cm.; Note: Holograph in ink.; Reference no.: 103.; Access points: David, Mack Kramer, Alex Whitney, Joan (Box-folder 30/8)
      - Candy [1945] / by Mack David, Joan Whitney and Alex Kramer., Full score; 11 leaves; 35.5 x 40.5 cm.; Note: Manuscript in pencil by Gene Porter.; Reference no.: 103.; Access points: David, Mack Kramer, Alex Whitney, Joan (Box-folder 42/2)
      - Clarisse / by George Joyner., Lead sheet (music and words); 1 p.; 27.5 cm.; Note: Negative photostat of holograph.; Access points: Joyner, George (Box-folder 30/9)
      - Confirmation / by Charlie Parker See: Hot house
      - Cupid / by George Joyner., Lead sheet; 3 p.; 32 cm.; Note: Holograph in pencil. Includes lyrics in ink on verso.; Access points: Joyner, George (Box-folder 30/10)
      - Empathy / by Sam Most., Instrumental parts; 4 leaves; various sizes.; Note: Holographs in pencil.; Access points: Most, Sam (Box-folder 30/11)
      - Ensenada / by John Dennis., Lead sheet; 1 p.; 32 cm.; Note: Holograph in ink.; Access points: Dennis, John (Box-folder 30/12)
      - Everything I have is yours / by Burton Lane and Harold Adamson., Lead sheet; 1 p.; 28 cm.; Note: Manuscript in pencil by Charles Mingus. On verso: The man I love.; Access points: Adamson, Harold Lane, Burton (Box-folder 30/13)
      - Evil / by Elliott Cola., Instrumental part; 1 p.; 45.5 cm.; Note: Holograph in ink.; Access points: Cola, Elliott (Box-folder 42/3)
      - Hommage à Mingus / by Antoine Duliamel., Full score; 21 p.; 27 x 35 cm.; Note: Holograph in ink. Inscribed on title page: In this day of November in Paris with all my wishes - A. Duliamel.; Access points: Duliamel, Antoine (Box-folder 30/14)
      - Hot house / by Charlie Parker., Chord chart. 1 p.; 31.5 cm.; Note: Manuscript in pencil in unknown hand. This leaf also includes chord charts for another Parker tune Confirmation, the bass part for Thelonius Monk's 'Round midnight, and bass part for the Dizzy Gillespie/Charlie Parker tune Shaw' nuff.; Access points: Parker, Charlie (Yardbird) (Box-folder 30/15)
      - [I] can't get started / by Vernon Duke and Ira Gershwin., Chord chart; 1 leaf; 31.5 cm.; Note: Manuscript in pencil by Charles Mingus. This leaf also includes chord charts for Thad's tune, More of the same, and a fragment of No greater love.; Reference no.: 199.; Access points: Duke, Vernon Gershwin, Ira (Box-folder 30/16)
      - I can't get started / by Vernon Duke and Ira Gershwin., Chord chart; 1 p.; 31.5 cm.; Note: Manuscript in pencil by Charles Mingus. This item includes additional unidentified music notation.; Reference no.: 199.; Access points: Duke, Vernon Gershwin, Ira (Box-folder 30/17)
      - I can't get started / by Vernon Duke and Ira Gershwin., Bass part; 2 p.; 31.5 cm.; Note: Manuscript in pencil by Charles Mingus.; Reference no.: 199.; Access points: Duke, Vernon Gershwin, Ira (Box-folder 30/18)
      - I left my heart in San Francisco / by Cross Douglass and George Cory., Instrumental parts; pagination varies; 32 cm.; Note: Copyist's manuscript in ink, piano part in pencil.; Reference no.: 193.; Access points: Cory, George Douglass, Cross (Box-folder 30/19)
      - I'll go on loving you / by Frances Lampert., Piano-vocal score; 3 p.; 31.5 cm.; Note: Copyist's manuscript in ink.; Access points: Lampert, Frances (Box-folder 30/20)
      - I'll never smile again / by Ruth Lowe., Condensed score; 3 p.; 30.5 cm.; Note: Manuscript in pencil by Charles Mingus.; Reference no.: 191.; Access points: Lowe, Ruth (Box-folder 30/21)
      - I'm not afraid of the world anymore / by Elliott Cola., Trumpet part; 1 p.; 28 cm.; Note: Holograph in ink.; Access points: Cola, Elliott (Box-folder 30/22)
      - It's so groovy / by Elliott Cola., Instrumental parts; 1 p.; 45.5 cm.; Note: Holograph in ink.; Access points: Cola, Elliott (Box-folder 42/4)
      - Just short of way out / by Bill Tennyson., Lead sheet; 1 p.; 31.5 cm.; Note: Holograph in pencil.; Access points: Tennyson, Bill (Box-folder 30/23)
      - The love I left behind / by John True., Lead sheet; 1 p.; 31.5 cm.; Note: Holograph in ink; lyrics included.; Access points: True, John (Box-folder 30/24)
      - Lush life / by Billy Strayhorn., Condensed score; 2 p.; 32 cm.; Note: Holograph in pencil with holograph ink markings.; Access points: Strayhorn, Billy (Box-folder 30/25)
      - Lush life / by Billy Strayhorn., Instrumental parts; pagination varies; 32 cm.; Note: Copyist's manuscripts in ink with holograph ink markings.; Access points: Strayhorn, Billy (Box-folder 30/26)
      - The man I love / by George and Ira Gershwin., Lead sheet (instrumental); 1 p.; 28 cm.; Note: Manuscript in pencil by Charles Mingus. On verso of: Everything I have is yours. See September song verso for bass part for The man I love.; Reference no.: 194.; Access points: Gershwin, George Gershwin, Ira (Box-folder 30/27)
      - [The] man I love / by George and Ira Gershwin., Full score; 2 p.; 34 cm.; Note: Manuscript in pencil by Charles Mingus.; Reference no.: 194.; Access points: Gershwin, George Gershwin, Ira (Box-folder 30/28)
      - [The] man I love / by George and Ira Gershwin., Full score (incomplete); 30.5 x 40.5 cm.; Note: Manuscript in pencil by Charles Mingus.; Reference no.: 194.; Access points: Gershwin, George Gershwin, Ira (Box-folder 42/5)
      - Memories of you / by Eubie Blake and Andy Razaf., Condensed score; 1 p.; 31.5 cm.; Note: Manuscript in pencil by Charles Mingus. On verso: Simple.; Reference no.: 196.; Access points: Blake, Eubie Razaf, Andy (Box-folder 30/29)
      - Miles of time / by J. Lowe., Piano score; 1 p.; 33.5 cm.; Note: Holograph in pencil.; Access points: Lowe, Ruth (Box-folder 30/30)
      - Night and day / by Cole Porter., Full score; 2 + 1 p.; 31.5 cm.; Note: Manuscript in pencil by Charles Mingus.; Reference no.: 190.; Access points: Porter, Cole (Box-folder 30/31)
      - Mo sky / by Elliott Cola., Song lyrics and full score (incomplete); 2 p.; 31.5 cm.; Note: Manuscript song lyrics in pencil in hand of Elliott Cola; manuscript full score in pencil on verso by Charles Mingus.; Access points: Cola, Elliott (Box-folder 30/32)
      - Not another Gershwin / by J. Lowe., Piano score; 1 p.; 28 cm.; Note: Holograph in ink.; Access points: Lowe, Ruth (Box-folder 30/33)
      - Odyssey / by John Dennis., Lead sheet; 2 leaves.; 32 cm.; Note: Holograph in ink.; Access points: Dennis, John (Box-folder 30/34)
      - Prophet of love / by John True., Lead sheet;. 1 p.; 31.5 cm.; Note: Holograph in ink; includes lyrics.; Access points: True, John (Box-folder 30/35)
      - Red dog blues / by Frank Davenport., Full score; 4 p.; 31.5 cm.; Note: Manuscript in pencil by Charles Mingus. Dated at head: Sept. 29, 1944.; Access points: Davenport, Frank (Box-folder 30/36)
      - Saxidental / by Richard Carter., Piano score; 1 p.; 33 cm. (3 copies).; Note: Photocopy of holograph.; Access points: Carter, Richard (Box-folder 30/37)
      - Scherzo: for quartet and strings / by Phil Moore., Bass part; 4 p.; 31.5 cm.; Note: Manuscript in ink with pencil markings throughout.; Access points: Moore, Phil (Box-folder 30/38)
      - Screen cut 3 / by Ralph Burns., Condensed score; 2 p.; 31.5 cm.; Note: Manuscript in pencil by Charles Mingus.; Access points: Burns, Ralph (Box-folder 30/39)
      - September song / by Maxwell Anderson and Kurt Weill., Bass part; 1 p.; 30.5 cm.; Note: Manuscript in ink and pencil by Charles Mingus. Includes bass parts to The man I love (channel only), Tenderly, and It takes an earth quaker.; Access points: Anderson, Maxwell Weill, Kurt (Box-folder 30/40)
      - Seven moons / by John Dennis., Lead sheet; 1 p.; 31.5 cm.; Note: Holograph in ink.; Access points: Dennis, John (Box-folder 30/41)
      - Simple variations on Chopin / adaptation by Sam Most., Instrumental parts; pagination varies; various sizes.; Holographs in ink and pencil.; Access points: Most, Sam (Box-folder 30/42)
      - Sophisticated lady / music by Duke Ellington; words by Irving Mills and Mitchell Parish., Chord chart; 1 p.; 28 x 35.5 cm.; Note: Manuscript in ink.; Access points: Ellington, Duke Mills, Irving Parish, Mitchell (Box-folder 30/43)
      - Steam wheel / by J. Lowe., Condensed score; 4 leaves.; 33 cm.; Note: Holograph in pencil.; Access points: Lowe, Ruth (Box-folder 30/44)
      - Stormy weather / by Ted Koehler and Harold Arlen., Instrumental parts (piano and drums only); 2 leaves.; 32 cm.; Note: Manuscript in ink with markings in pencil by Charles Mingus.; Reference no.: 197.; Access points: Arlen, Harold Koehler, Ted (Box-folder 30/45)
      - Synchobop / by Sam Most., Instrumental parts; pagination varies; various sizes.; Note: Holographs in pencil.; Access points: Most, Sam (Box-folder 30/46)
      - Tea for two / by Irving Caesar and Vincent Youmans., Full score; 10 leaves., 30.5 x 40.5 cm.; Note: Copyist's manuscript in pencil.; Reference no.: 195.; Access points: Caesar, Irving Youmans, Vincent (Box-folder 42/6)
      - Tea for two: study in lines / by Irving Caesar and Vincent Youmans., Instrumental parts; pagination varies; 31.5 cm.; Note: Manuscripts in ink and pencil by C. Mingus. Item includes references to the tunes Perdido and Prisoner of love.; Reference no.: 195.; Access points: Caesar, Irving Youmans, Vincent (Box-folder 30/47)
      - This is me / by Elliott Cola., Instrumental parts; 1 p.; 45.5 cm.; Note: Holograph in ink.; Access points: Cola, Elliott (Box-folder 42/7)
      - Timboro / by Fernando Sandoval (Jarocho)., Lead sheet; 2 p.; 25 cm.; Note: Holograph in ink. Inscribed on cover: To Great Charles Mingus and his group - Sincerely, Fernando Sandoval (Jarocho), San Francisco, Calif., 26 - May - 1964. (Box-folder 30/48)
      - Two pairs twins / by Fernando Sandoval (Jarocho)., Lead sheet; 1 p.; 32 cm.; Note: Holograph in ink. Inscribed at bottom: To Great Charles Mingus and his Quintet - Sincerely, Fernando Sandoval (Jarocho), San Francisco, Calif., 26 - May - 1964. (Box-folder 30/49)
      - [Unknown] / by Edward Snead., Piano-vocal score; 1 p.; 30 cm.; Note: Holograph in ink on transparent paper.; Access points: Snead, Edward (Box-folder 30/50)
      - [Untitled] / by J. Lowe., Full score; 2 leaves.; 33.5 cm.; Note: Holograph in pencil.; Access points: Lowe, Ruth (Box-folder 30/51)
      - Walkin' on air / by Frances Lampert., Lead sheet; 1 p.; 31.5 cm.; Note: Ozalid copy of holograph. At head: Copyright by Frances Lampert, 1968.; Access points: Lampert, Frances (Box-folder 30/52)
      - What's this I hear you say? / by Frances Lampert., Lead sheet; 1 p.; 31.5 cm.; Note: Ozalid copy of holograph. At head: Copyright by Frances Lampert.; Access points: Lampert, Frances (Box-folder 30/53)
      - You and me / by George Joyner., Lead sheet (music and words); 2 p.; 32 cm.; Note: Holograph music notation in pencil; words on verso in ink.; Access points: Joyner, George (Box-folder 30/54)
      - You go to my head / by Haven Gillespie and J. Fred Coots., Condensed score; 3 p.; 27.5 cm.; Note: Manuscript in pencil, hand unknown.; Reference no.: 202.; Access points: Coots, J. Fred Gillespie, Haven (Box-folder 30/55)
      - [You go to my] head / by Haven Gillespie and J. Fred Coots., Full score; 3 p.; 28 cm.; Note: Manuscript in pencil by Charles Mingus.; Reference no.: 202.; Access points: Coots, J. Fred Gillespie, Haven (Box-folder 30/56)
      - You're my everything / by Mort Dixon, Joe Young and Harry Warren., Condensed score; 1 p.; 27.5 cm.; Note: Manuscript in pencil in unknown hand.; Reference no.: 215.; Access points: Dixon, Mort Warren, Harry Young, Joe (Box-folder 30/57)
  - Printed Music (Box 29, Box 31)
    - Printed Music by Mingus (Box 29)
      - Goodbye pork pie hat / Sy Johnson, arr. Delevan, NY: Kendor Music, Inc., 1980., Full score and instrumental parts; 4 + 12 leaves; Note: Photocopy of copyist's manuscript.; Copyright by Jazz Workshop, Inc., c1972,; Reference no.: 033.; Access points: Johnson, Sy (Box-folder 29/1)
      - More than a fake book. New York: Jazz Workshop, Inc., 1991., A compilation of lead sheets to Mingus compositions; 160 p.; Date: c1991; Note: Distributed by Hal Leonard Publishing Corp.; Note: Includes photocopies of original holograph manuscripts. (Box-folder 29/2)
      - The musical styles of Charles Mingus / Sy Johnson, arr. New York: Warner Bros. Publications, Inc., n.d., A compilation of condensed scores to Mingus compositions; 70 p.; Reference no.: 291.; Access points: Johnson, Sy (Box-folder 29/3)
      - Revelations. Newton, Mass.: Margun Music, Inc., 1976., Full score; 40 p.; Note: copyright by Jazz Workshop, Inc., 1976.; Note: Composed by Charles Mingus in 1957. Laid in: Two handwritten notes to Mingus and 1 page typescript "Errata" sheet.; Reference no.: 073. (Box-folder 29/4)
    - Printed Music by Others (Box 31)
      - Acerca de ti (about you) / by Victor Ruiz Pazos. Mexico, D.F.: Promotora Hispano Americana de Música, 1964., Instrumental parts; pagination varies.; Date: c1964; Note: Inscribed on title page: To great Charlie Mingus and his Quintet, Sincerely Fernando Sandoval (Jarocho), friend of Composer Victor Ruiz Pazos (Vitillo), San Francisco, Calif., 26-May-1964.; Access points: Pazos, Victor Ruiz (Box-folder 31/1)
      - Alone together / words by Howard Dietz; music by Arthur Schwartz. New York: Harms, Inc., 1932., Piano-vocal score; 5 p.; Date: c1932; Note: From the musical revue "Flying Colors". Chord indications and other markings in pencil by Charles Mingus.; Access points: Dietz, Howard Schwartz, Arthur (Box-folder 31/2)
      - [Hanon, the virtuoso pianist in 60 exercises]: no. 8 and no. 9 / by Charles-Louis Hanon. Chicago: Paradiso Publishers, n.d., Piano solo (incomplete); 2 p.; Note: Chord indications and other pencil markings by Charles Mingus.; Access points: Hanon, Charles-Louis (Box-folder 31/3)
      - I've got a crush on you / music by George Gershwin; words by Ira Gershwin. New York: New World Music Corporation; Harms, Inc., 1930., Piano-vocal score; 5 p.; Date: c1930; Note: From the musical comedy "Strike Up the Band".; Access points: Gershwin, George Gershwin, Ira (Box-folder 31/4)
      - La marcha de Sanson (Samson's march) / by Victor Ruiz Pazos. Mexico, D.F.: Promotora Hispano Americana de Música, 1964., Instrumental parts; pagination varies.; Date: c1964; Note: Inscribed on title page: To great Charlie Mingus and his Quintet, Sincerely Fernando Sandoval (Jarocho), friend of Composer Victor Ruiz Pazos (Vitillo), San Francisco, Calif., 26-May-1964.; Access points: Pazos, Victor Ruiz (Box-folder 31/5)
      - Slippin' for a pippin / music by Frances Lampert; arranged by Walter L. Rosemont. Theatre Arts Corporation: Middleton, Conn., [1964]., Piano-vocal score; 3 p.; Note: Copyright by Frances Lampert; Access points: Lampert, Frances Rosemont, Walter L. (Box-folder 31/6)
      - Vals de Norma (Norma's waltz) / by Victor Ruiz Pazos. Mexico, D.F.: Promotora Hispano Americana de Música, 1964., Instrumental parts; pagination varies.; Date: c1964; Note: Inscribed on title page: To great Charlie Mingus and his Quintet, Sincerely Fernando Sandoval (Jarocho), friend of Composer Victor Ruiz Pazos (Vitillo), San Francisco, Calif., 26-May-1964.; Access points: Pazos, Victor Ruiz (Box-folder 31/7)
- Writings (Box 49-53)
  The Writings series is represented by 3 subseries. The Writings By Mingus subseries consists of Mingus' controversial autobiographical work, Beneath the Underdog; Mingus' manuscript liner notes (written for record album jackets); and articles published in serials. The Writings About Mingus subseries consists of articles on Mingus' biography; articles and reviews relating to his literary work Beneath the Underdog; articles on Mingus Dynasty (the New York- based jazz orchestra established after his death as a tribute to him and his contributions in music); and articles about his widow, Susan Graham Mingus. The Miscellaneous Writings subseries consists of written works on a variety of subjects not necessarily relating to Mingus.
  Writings series is arranged as follows:
  Writings by Mingus, arranged alphabetically by title.
  Writings about Mingus:
  Articles bound in serials, arranged alphabetically by article title.
  Loose articles & clippings, arranged chronologically by article date.
  Miscellaneous writings [film work, poetry, short stroies], arranged alphabetically by subject then by title.
  - Writings by CM (Box 45-46, Box 52)
    - Manuscripts
      - "A living benefit for Mingus": typescript; 1 p. (Box-folder 45/1)
      - Beneath the underdog, #1: typescript with holograph ink and pencil markings; pagination varies (Box-folder 45/2)
      - Beneath the underdog, #2: holograph in ink and pencil and typescript; pagination varies (Box-folder 45/3)
      - Beneath the underdog, #3: typescript with holograph ink and pencil markings; 86 p.; soft bound (Box-folder 45/4)
      - Beneath the underdog, #4: typescript with holograph ink and pencil markings; pp. 181-274 (Box-folder 45/5)
      - Beneath the underdog, #5: typescript with holograph ink and pencil markings; pp. 275-374 (Box-folder 45/6)
      - Beneath the underdog, #6: typescript with holograph ink and pencil markings; pp. 375-459; soft bound (Box-folder 45/7)
      - Beneath the underdog, #7: typescript with holograph ink and pencil markings; pp. 460-596 (Box-folder 45/8)
      - Beneath the underdog, #8: typescript with holograph ink and pencil markings; pp. 597-739 (Box-folder 45/9)
      - Beneath the underdog, #9: typescript with holograph ink and pencil markings; pp. 740-875 (Box-folder 45/10)
      - Beneath the underdog, King's 2nd Draft: typescript; pp. 1-99 (Box-folder 46/1)
      - Beneath the underdog, King's 2nd Draft: typescript; pp. 100-199 (Box-folder 46/2)
      - Beneath the underdog, King's 2nd Draft: typescript; pp. 200-299 (Box-folder 46/3)
      - Beneath the underdog, King's 2nd Draft: typescript; pp. 300-381 (Box-folder 46/4)
      - Beneath the underdog, Miscellaneous (Box-folder 46/5)
    - Liner Notes (Box-folder 46/6)
      - "Let my childeren hear music": tyoescripts with holograph markings in pencil and ink; original photocopied
      - Miscellaneous
    - Miscellaneous notes (Box-folder 46/7)
      - Published [in serials, stored in oversized container]
      - "An open letter to the avante garde" [article]: Changes, Issue No. 82, June 1973, p. 26 (2 copies) (Box-folder 52/1)
      - "Charles Mingus answers John S. Wilson of the N.Y. Tribune" [article]: Changes, Issue 71, March 15, 1972, p. 1 (Box-folder 52/2)
  - Writings About CM (Box 47, Box 50-53)
    - Articles & Clippings: Bound in Serials
      - Domestic Serials [stored without folders, arranged alphabetically by article title] (Box 49)
        - "A reporter at large: Mingus at peace", by Whitney Balliet [article]: The New Yorker, May 29, 1971, p. 42 (2 copies)
        - "About Charlie Mingus", by Donald heckman [article]: The American Record Guide, Aug. 1962, p. 916 (2 copies)
        - "Blindfold test: Charles Mingus", by Leonard Feather [article]: Down Beat, April 28, 1960, p. 49
        - "Blindfold test: Charles Mingus #2", by Leonard Feather [article]: Down Beat, May 12, 1960, p. 39 (2 copies)
        - "Charles Mingus: April 22, 1922 - January 5, 1979", by Rafi Zabor [article]: Musician, Player, & Listener, No. 17, April 1979, p. 22
        - "Charles Mingus: better git it in your soul", by Joe B. Klee [article]: Jazz Interactions, Jan./Feb. 1972, p. 5
        - "Charles Mingus: moves", by Neil Tesser [review]: Down Beat, Aug. 15, 1974, p. 31
        - "Charles Mingus: the underdog meets Joni Mitchell", by Ben Sidran [article]: Rolling Stone, Issue No. 282, Jan. 11, 1979, p. 33 (Box-folder 52/3)
        - "Charles Mingus presents: the Charles Mingus Quartet" [review]: Changes, Vol. 3, No. 2, June 15, 1971, p. 13 (2 copies) (Box-folder 52/4)
        - "Dance" [article]: New York, Sept. 13, 1971, p. 54 (2 copies) (Box 49)
        - "Down Beat 36th Annual Readers' Poll": Down Beat, Dec. 23, 1971; Mingus elected into Down Beat Hall of Fame
        - "Down Beat 44th Annual Readers' Poll": Down Beat, Dec. 1979; Mingus elected Jazz Musician of the Year, and ranked first in the DB "Composer" category
        - "Gallery", by Sy Johnson [article]: Jazz Magazine, Spring 1978, Vol. 2, No. 3, p. 46
        - "The gospel according to Mingus: disciples carry the tune", by Bret Primack [article]: Down Beat, Dec. 7, 1978, p. 12 (2 copies). Note: Issue also includes review of Mingus' recording of Cumbia & Jazz Fusion.
        - "Jazz at the White House" [article]: BMI: The Many Worlds of Music, Issue 3 1978, p. 16
        - "Mingus, Charles" [biography]: Current Biography, Vol. 32, No. 2, Feb. 1971, p. 26
        - "My man Mingus" [article]: Changes, Vol. 3, No. 2, June 15, 1971, p. 15 (2 copies) (Box-folder 52/4)
        - "Salt peanuts at 1600", by Bill Brower [article]: Musician, Player & Listener, Issue No. 14, Oct. 1978, p. 43 (Box 49)
      - Foreign Serials [stored loosely, arranged according to size]
        - "Beknopte discografie van Charlie Mingus", [by] H. De Wild [article]: Rhythme, No. 71, 15 Aug. 1955, p. 8 (Box 50)
        - "Breve viaggio a New York", [by] Giancarlo Testoni [article]: Musica Jazz, N. 7-8 (187), Luglio-Agosto 1962, p. 12
        - "Charles Mingus" [article]: Jazz Wereld, Nummer 30, juli 1970, p. 27. Note: Issue also includes reviews of two Mingus recordings
        - "Charlie Mingus sur la sellette", [blindfold test by Leonard Feather]: Jazz Magazine, No. 61, juillet-aout 1960, p. 16
        - "Chazz Minkus", [by] Joāo Marcos Coelho [article]: Abre Alas, Nov. 1979, p. 130
        - "Debut-records" [article]: Musikrevue, April 1957, p. 105. Note: Mingus is also mentioned in a review of two Thad Jones recordings, p. 126
        - "Ed ora anche Mingus...",[by] Arrigo Polillio [article]: Jazz Musica, Febbraio 1979, p. 2 (2 copies)
        - "Jazz en Nueva York (y en Montevideo)" [article]: Sábados Show, 28 de Mayo, 1977, p. 11. Note: Mingus is also featured in an article titled Vista de un famoso "jazzman" on back cover of same
        - "Mingus fra Brande: de nye plader på Debut", [by] Knud H. Ditlevsen [article]: Musikrevue, Oktober 1957, p. 250
        - "The White House all stars", by Lee Jeske [article]: Jazz Journal International, Vol. 31, No. 9, Sept. 1978, p. 26
    - Articles & Clippings: Loose [photocopies]
      - Beneath the underdog (Box-folder 47/1)
      - Charles Mingus Biography (Box-folder 47/2)
      - Charles Mingus Tributes (Box-folder 47/3)
      - Domestic Clips
        - 1950s (Box-folder 47/4)
        - 1960s (Box-folder 47/5)
        - 1970-75 (Box-folder 47/6)
        - 1976-81 (except 1977) (Box-folder 47/7)
        - 1977 (Box-folder 47/8)
        - Unknown source and/or date (Box-folder 47/9)
      - Foreign Clips
        - 1956-80 (Box-folder 47/10)
        - Unknown source and/or date
      - Mingus Dynasty (Box-folder 47/11)
      - Susan (Sue) Graham Mingus (Box-folder 47/12)
      - Miscellaneous (Box-folder 47/13)
    - Oversized Clips
      - Domestic (Box-folder 51/1, Box-folder 53/1)
      - Foreign (Box-folder 51/2, Box-folder 53/2)
    - Newsletters, Press Releases, & Bulletins (Box-folder 47/14)